Inventory of the Academy For Educational Development Records, 1956-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
- Other Institutions/Associations/Commissions. (Box No. 29-30.)
  - "Performance and Potential: A Report on a Consultation Program in Grantsmanship." Hadassah: The Women's Zionist Organization of America, In c. 1980, 1-657 (Box 30.)
  - Alliance for Greatness: A Comprehensive Study of Higher Education in the State of Delaware. Higher Educational Aid Advisory Commission, State of Delaware. 1969, 35
  - "The Use of Libraries and the Conditions that Promote their Use." National Advisory Commission on Libraries. 1967, 36
  - Seidl, Anthony E., and Sidney G. Tickton, Long-Range Planning for Catholic Schools: A Guide for Action, 1969, 48.1
  - "A Plan for Education Programs of the National Air and Space Museum of the Smithsonian Institution." 1977, 315
  - "Toward Financial Independence: Recommendations for an Augmented Fund-Raising Program for the National Council of Jewish Women," 1979, 486
  - Kubal, Larry A., ed., "International and Intercultural Education in the United States." World Studies Data Bank. 1975, 136.3
  - "International Education Contacts on U.S. Campuses: A Directory." World Studies Data Bank. 1974, 136.2
- Problems/Advisory/Exploratory/Overviews. (Box No. 31-38.)
  - Future Resources and Development, Inc., An Analysis of and Recommendations for Training in Group Operations. Connecticut General Life Insurance Company. 1970, FRD-1 (Box 31.)
  - Tickton, Sidney G., Tuition Aid Programs at Large Corporations, 1971, 32
  - Black Studies: How It Works at Ten Universities, 1971, -
  - "Background Materials for Black Studies Seminar." Vols. 1-2. 1970, 93
  - "Background Materials for Black Studies Seminar." Vol. 3. 1970, 93 (Box 32.)
  - "Final Report of the Advisory Panel on the Black Workshop," 1969, 84
  - "Improving the Nursing Training Project." Bridgeport Hospital School of Nursing. 1973, 166
  - Millett, John D., "Undergraduate Education and Political Science." Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching. n.d., 167
  - Millett, John D., Why Political Science? Explorations in Undergraduate Education. Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching. 1973, 167.A
  - Tickton, Sidney G., and Ronald Gross, "Major Problems Facing Public Schools in the Seventies," 1968, 47
  - Rauh, Morton A., and John D. Millett, "College Without Campus." Ottawa University. 1976, 299.1
  - Temporary State Commission on the Constitutional Convention of the State of New York, Education, 1967, 29 (Box 33.)
  - Tickton, Sidney G., "The Education Picture, 1966-1976," n.d., 19
  - Educational Change and Architectural Consequences: A Report on Facilities for Individualized Instruction. Educational Facilities Laboratory. 1968., 17
  - "Energy Management for Human Service Agencies." National Assembly of National Voluntary Health and Social Welfare Organizations. n.d., 5-640
  - Millett, John D., General Education in the Decades Ahead, 1975, -
  - Kinder, William A., "High School Homework Helpers." New York City Office of Educational Evaluation. 1974, 217
  - "Investments in the Improvement of Postsecondary Education," 1978, 428
  - "Legal Education Advancement Planning (LEAP): An Introductory Study of Minority Law Student Development Potentials," 1971, 124 (Box 34.)
  - Leadership in Public Education Study: A Look at the Overlooked, 1972, 103
  - Bussis, Dale E., and Rita Senf, "An Evaluation of Project LIVE (Learning through Industry and Volunteer Educators): 1974-1975 School Year," n.d., 239
  - Wells, Herman B., The Legislature and Higher Education in New York State: A Report by the Legislature's Consultant on Higher Education, 1964, 3
  - "Study of Campus-Wide Governance." Lilly Endowment. 1975, 219
  - Millett, John D., "Report to the Special Committee on Restructuring the City University of New York," 1976, 219
  - Millett, John D., "Campuswide Governance, 1966-1976: A Report of Experience Drawn from Case Studies of Thirty Institutions," 1977, 219
  - Millett, John D., "Review of Governance and Management." Sangamon State University. 1977, 219 (Box 35.)
  - "An Analysis of Income/Expense Budget Models." University of Pittsburgh. 1976, 219.1
  - Bunting, Mary I., George Weathersby, and John D. Millett, "Report to the President of Barnard College," 1976, 219.2
  - Parker, Norman A., "A Study of the Support Operations of Independent Liberal Arts Colleges," 1975, 221
  - Tickton, Sidney G., Needed: A Ten Year College Budget. Fund for the Advancement of Education. 1961, -
  - "A Feasibility Study of Resources and Methods for Developing a Career Education Program in the World of Transportation." Newark Board of Education and New Jersey Department of Education. 1973, 150
  - "An Evaluation of the Initial Ten Lesson Segment of the World of Transportation Course." New Jersey Department of Education-Division of Vocational Education and Newark Board of Education. 1974, 185
  - "Planning for Declining Enrollments in Single High School Districts," n.d., 5-588
  - Tickton, Sidney G., "A Decade of Growth: A Profile of the Change in the Nation's Business, Educational, Governmental, and Social Welfare Activities, 1954-1964." 2 vols. 1965, 9 (Box 36.)
  - "The Reporting of Human Behavior: A Study of Bridge- Building between Behavioral Sciences and Journalism." Russell Sage Foundation. 1970 (2 copies), 78
  - AED Officers and Project Directors' Meeting (Staff Meeting #1). 1976. Proceedings, 1976, - (Box 37.)
  - "A Brief Status Report on the Voluntary Sector." Ford Foundation. 1979, 518
  - "Admissions/Recruitment: A Study of Costs and Practices in Independent Higher Education Institutions," 1978, 318
  - "Surplus School Space in New York City: The Problems, The Opportunity," 1980, 5-590
  - Murphy, Judith, and George Sullivan, Music in American Society. Music Educators National Conference. 1968, -
  - "Training the Total Learner." Diversified Education and Research Corporation. 1968, 53
  - Alter, Chester M., "A Profile of the United Negro College Fund Members: Past, Present, and Future," 1968, 33
  - "Confidential Report to the Director of Wave Hill," 1969, 59
  - "Why Non-Starts?" Famous Artists Schools. 1968, 44 (Box 38.)
  - "Medical Education for Wyoming: Imperative for Improved Health Care," 1972, 144
  - Tickton, Sidney G., The Year-Round Campus Catches On. Fund for the Advancement of Education. 1963, -
  - "Brazilian Travelling Seminar on the Improvement of University Teaching in U.S.," 1977, 365
- Policy Studies in Education. (Box No. 38-41.)
  - Paul, Regina H., "Career Education for Small School Districts." American Association of School Administrators. 1978, P-411 (Box 38.)
  - "Career Education Program for Individualizing Career Education for the Handicapped through Competency- Based Learning Modules." Arlington, Virginia, Public Schools. 1977, P-197
  - "Survey of Educational Goals." School District of Brown Deer, Wisconsin. 1978, P-351
  - Aslanian, Carol B., "Career Education and Business Education: A Committed Partnership: A Survey of Current Practices and Needed Assistance." National Business Education Association. 1979, P-523
  - American Association of Community and Junior Colleges, "An Evaluation of Demonstrating Career Education in Community Colleges," 1980, P-493
  - Aslanian, Carol B., Beatrice L. Gross, and Archibald McDowell III, "Youth Employment and Training Program, 1978-80." Center for Career and Occupational Education, Board of Education of the City of New York. 1980, P-608
  - "Final Plan for the Youth Employment and Demonstration Projects Act." Center for Career and Occupational Education, Board of Education of the City of New York. 1978, P-350.07 (Box 39.)
  - Macaulay, Lynne D., and Janet M. Doeden, "Special Delivery: A Television Series about Handicapping Conditions." WNVT-TV, Annandale, Virginia. 3 vols. 1978, P-905
  - "Assessment of Attitudinal Development and Cognitive Learning." Colorado Experience-Based Career Education Model. 1978 (2 copies), P-389
  - "Looking Ahead to the 1978 Forum on Nationwide Dissemination Activities in Education: A Planning Document." U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare. 1978, P-350.01
  - Brickell, Henry M., Minimum Competency Testing. Education Commission of the States. 1978, P-409
  - Brickell, Henry M., Regina H. Paul, and Diane E. Rusling, "An Evaluation of the National Committee, Arts for the Handicapped." 1979, P-560 (Box 40.)
  - "Career Education Assessment." Iroquois Central School District. 1978, P-446
  - "Evaluation Report on the Unit Now and the Future." Jefferson County School District, Lakewood, Colorado. 1978, P-195
  - "Final Evaluation Report for Placement of Junior and Senior High School Students in Nontraditional Career Exploration Experiences in the Community." Jefferson County, Colorado, Public Schools. 1978, P-388
  - "An Evaluation of Demonstrating Career Education in Community Colleges." American Association of Community and Junior Colleges. 1978, P-374
  - "Career Education in North Carolina: A Needs Assessment," 1977, P-906
  - "Supplying Policy Information to Advisory Councils on Vocational Education." New York State Advisory Council on Vocational Education. 1978, P-901
  - "Evaluation of 1976-1977 New York State Projects in Career Education." New York State Advisory Council on Vocational Education. 1977, P-912
  - Paul, Regina H., "Final Evaluation Report for the Rockland County Career Internship Program." Rockland County Board of Cooperative Educational Services, West Nyack, New York. 1978, P-366 (Box 41.)
  - Paul, Regina H., and Henry M. Brickell, "Summary of the 1978 Very Special Arts Festivals Model Site Program and Plan for the 1978-79 Program," 1978, P-412
  - "Evaluation of the Southern Tier Central Career Education Program." Steuben-Allegany Board of Cooperative Educational Services, Bath, New York. 1978, P-397
- Schools. (Box No. 41-60.)
  - Irwin, Judith T., ed., The Campus Resources of Higher Education in the United States of America: A Taxonomy of Types and a Geographical Distribution,1973 (2 copies), - (Box 41.)
  - Moon, Rexford G., Jr., Report to Albertus Magnus College, 1975, 252
  - "Alphonsus College: A Study of Its Plans for 1972-75," 1972, 130
  - "To Improve Cooperation: A Plan for the Organization of the Atlanta University Center," 1970, 64
  - "Management Audit of Beaver College," 1977, 303 (Box 42.)
  - "Organization and Financial Management of Bowdoin College," 1971, 105
  - "External Evaluation No. 4: Advanced Institutional Development Program." Bowie State College. 1980, 3-561
  - "Possible Areas for Public Aid for the University of Bridgeport," 1970, 100 (Box 43.)
  - "Study for the Joseph Bulova School of Watchmaking Made at the Request of the Bulova Fund, Inc.," 1974, 211
  - "The University of Bridgeport in a Decade of Change," 1971, 100
  - Moon, Rexford G., Jr., "Cabrini College Admissions Management Plan," 1977, 304
  - "Report on the Physical Plant Department at Central State University," 1976, 235.1
  - "An Evaluation of the Advanced Institutional Development Program at Central State University," 1978, 235.2
  - "A Review of Computer Uses and Needs at Central State University," 1976, 261.4 (Box 44.)
  - "A Study of Recruiting, Admissions, and Retention at Central State University," 1976, 261
  - "Planning Guidelines for Central State University," 1980, 3-611
  - "Implementation Plan for the Administrative Reorganization of Chicago State University," 1979, 391/391.1
  - Millett, John D., "Departmental Evaluation, University of Cincinnati," 1976, -
  - "Recommendations for a Long-Range Plan for the College for Human Services." Women's Talent Corps, Inc. 1970, 76
  - "Long-Range Plan Development." Community College of Baltimore. 1980, 3-683
  - "Pilot Plan Studies." Connecticut College. 1972, 140
  - "Administrative Structure and Operation of the University of Connecticut," 1970, 83 (Box 45.)
  - "Report on Staffing Patterns and Expenditures for Support Programs at Connecticut College," 1977, 336
  - "The Future of Davidson College," 1969, 67
  - "The University of Delaware and Teacher Education," 1964, 5
  - Detroit Institute of Technology: Today, Tomorrow, and in the Generation Ahead, 1968, 30
  - "A Report on the UDC Community Needs Assessment." University of District of Columbia. 1979, 441
  - "Presentation to the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia," 1979, 529
  - "Transactional Systems, Planning and Management Support Systems, and Planning at UDC: #6." University of the District of Columbia. 1979, 553 (Box 46.)
  - "Master Plan: The University of the District of Columbia: Excellence in the 1980s," 1980, 3-553
  - "Eastern New Mexico University: External Evaluation #1: Strengthening Developing Institutional Programs," 1980, 3-649
  - "Evaluation of the Learning Center: Its Structure, Services, and Future Profile." Eastern New Mexico University. 1980, 3-649 (Box 47.)
  - "Eckerd College 1981: Proposed New Directions," 1976, 274
  - "Eckerd College: A Plan for Action," 1977, 274.2
  - Millett, John D., "Report on Elmhurst College," 1975, 248
  - "Fairleigh Dickinson University: Prospects for the Future," 1968, 39
  - "Making a Market: A Program of Educational and Industrial Relations for Franklin Institute of Boston," 1974, 177
  - "Fuller: The Decade Ahead." Fuller Theological Seminary. 1974, 193
  - "An Evaluation of the Undergraduate Curriculum at Gallaudet College: Study Design and Research Methodology," 1980, 3-650 (Box 48.)
  - "A Review of Facts and Perceptions of the Undergraduate Curriculum at Gallaudet College," 1980, 3-650
  - Governors State University. Report. 1973, 179
  - "The Future of Public Education in Dobbs Ferry and Hastingson-Hudson." Dobbs Ferry, New York, and Hastings-on- Hudson, New York, Public Schools. 1971, 97
  - "Report of General Survey of Hollins College," 1979, 552
  - "Second-Year External Evaluation of the Advanced Institutional Development Program at Hood College, l979/80," 1980, 3-002
  - "Educational Needs Assessment of the Tri-County Area of Hood College," 1980, 3-002
  - "Houston Community College: Internal Environment," 1980, 3-667 (Box 49.)
  - "A Guide to Improving Management at John Jay College of Criminal Justice," 1974, 184
  - Weintraub, Ruth G., "Concluding Observations and Recommendations on the Middle College Program." LaGuardia Community College. 1976, 229.2
  - "A Final Report on the Middle College Program." LaGuardia Community College. 1975, 229
  - "Partnership in New York City's Future: A Long-Range Plan for LaGuardia Community College," 1978, 395
  - "Change for Survival: A Report to the President of the Brooklyn Center of Long Island University." 1971, 92
  - "Study on Feasibility of Merging Lowell Technological Institute and Lowell State College," 1972, 151
  - "Planning for the Rebirth of Mackinac College," 1971, 108.1 (Box 50.)
  - "Randolph-Macon Woman's College: Organization and Administrative Support," 1975, 233
  - "Malcolm-King: New Higher Education Opportunities for Harlem." Malcolm-King Harlem College Extension. 1974, 171
  - Maryland Fire and Rescue Institute, "A Plan to Establish and Operate Regional Centers for Training Fire Fighters and Rescue Personnel in the State of Maryland." University of Maryland. 1976, 272
  - "Report of the Five Year Projection Committee.", 109.l,2
  - "Final Report to Board of Trustees, Menlo School and College," 1969, 61
  - "Toward Improved Student Development at Mercy College," 1974, 210 (Box 51.)
  - "Westchester's Need for Graduate Level Training in Elementary and Early Childhood Urban Education." Mercy College. 1974, 228
  - Moon, Rexford G., Jr. Report to Mercy College. 1976, 283
  - "External Evaluation of the Strengthening Developing Institutions Program at Mercy College of Dobbs Ferry. New York, 1979-80," 1980, 3-652
  - "Evaluation of Student Developmental Studies and Services." Mercy College. 1980, 652
  - "Memorandum on Activity 6: Continuing Education Strengthening Developing Institution Program (SDIP) Grant." Mercy College. 1980, 3-652
  - "A Possible Program of Instruction for the Western College of Miami University," 1975, 181
  - Miller, James G., "A Systems Analysis of the Roles of the Various Health Professions in the Drug Abuse Field." Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine. 1972, 120
  - Millett, John D., "Report on Enrollment and Costs: Minnesota Community College System," 1980, 552
  - "External Evaluation of Morgan State University's AIDP Supplemental Grant," 1980, 3-004 (Box 52.)
  - Morris Harvey College, "Morris Harvey College: Today, Tomorrow, and in the Decade Ahead," 1976, 133.4
  - "Preliminary Report of the Enrollment Projection Committee." Northeast Missouri State College. 1972, 122
  - "A Memorandum Regarding Affiliation or Merger of New Hampshire College and Daniel Webster College," 1980, 680
  - "Improvement of Existing Evening Program: Specifications of Continuing Education Possibilities: Part I: Employer Survey Findings." North Carolina Wesleyan College. 1980, 3-653
  - "Improvement of Existing Evening Program: Specifications of Continuing Education Possibilities: Part II: Resident Survey Findings." North Carolina Wesleyan College. 1980 (2 copies), 3-653
  - "Observations and Suggestions about North Park College and Theological Seminary," 1979, 552
  - "Summary Report of an Evaluation of the Learning Center and Related Programs at Oklahoma Christian College," 1970, 79 (Box 53.)
  - "Establishing a Formal Planning System." Ottawa University. 1977, 299
  - "Report to the Presidents of Pace University and New York University," 1974, 195
  - "Report to the President of the University of Pennsylvania Regarding Future Policies and Actions on Dormitory Operations and Dining Services," 1972, 127
  - "Proposal to Plan and Coordinate an Information System for the University of Pittsburgh," 1972, 131
  - Millett, John D. Report to the University of Pittsburgh. 1977, 131.3
  - "Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn," 1973, 158
  - "Pratt Institute: Final Report," 1970, 85 (Box 54.)
  - "Report on Governance at J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College, Richmond, Virginia," 1980, 3-552
  - "Report on Organization of the College of Arts and Sciences, University of Rhode Island," 1973, 174
  - Seidl, Anthony, and Sidney G. Tickton, "Proposal for Action by St. Edward's University," 1973, 163.1,2
  - "A Time to Consolidate Gains." St. Norbert College. 1971, 112
  - "New Modes of Service: The Challenge of Salem College," 1975, 226.2
  - Salem College. Report. 1974, 226 (Box 55.)
  - "Admissions Services Report." Salem College. 1976, 226.3
  - "Salem College Advanced Institutional Development Program: 1975-76 Status Report," 1976, 226.4
  - Tickton, Sidney G., "Fourth Year Report to the President on the Status of the Advanced Institutional Development Program." Salem College. 1978, 226.4
  - Millett, John D., "Report on Organization for Personnel Management." Sangamon State University. 1979, 552
  - "Report on the School of Education, University of Michigan," 1969, 63
  - "Draft Plan for the Future." University of Scranton. 1973, 149 (Box 56.)
  - "Stephens College: Design for the Future," 1973, 168
  - "Enrollment Projection." State University College of Technology at Utica/Rome. 1978, 454
  - "Trinity College Looks to the Future," 1980, 602
  - "Study Report: Tulane University," 1974, 214
  - "The Future Role and Scope of Tuskegee Institute," 1970, 69
  - "Tuskegee Institute Talent Search," 1971, 107 (Box 57.)
  - "In Support of Voluntary Education in the Military Services." U.S. Armed Forces Institute. 1974, 186
  - "A Consideration of Faculty Workload Policies at Twelve Liberal Arts Colleges." Vassar College. 1969, 70
  - "Problems, Recommendations, and Next-Steps." Villanova University. 1977, 405
  - "Report to Wells College," 1977, 339.2
  - "Meeting the Challenges and Opportunities for the l980s." Widener College. 1975, 245
  - "Survival for Wilson College: The Time for Stewardship and Sacrifice," 1974, 212
  - "The Sandburg Education Center: A Viable Concept in Living and Learning." Univesity of Wisconsin- Milwaukee. 1974, 213 (Box 58.)
  - "The Yeshiva University High Schools: A Look at the Past, Present, and Future," 1976, 296
  - "Yeshiva University 1976: An Analysis of the Present and Some Suggestions for the Future," 1976, 282
  - "The Feasibility of Establishing a Two-Year College in Los Angeles." Yeshiva University. 1976, 301
  - "Observations and Recommendations Concerning Some Aspects of Governance at Yeshiva University," 1978, 421
  - "Yeshiva University: An Approach to Retirement of Its Secured Long Term Debt: A Final Report to the Participant Banks," 1979, 648
  - Elmendorf, John, Transmitting Information about Experiments in Higher Education: New College as a Case Study, 1975, 172 (Box 59.)
  - "New Opportunities for Service: A Plan for the Future of the Charles E. Ellis Trust." Charles E. Ellis School for Girls. 1973, 183.1,2
  - Executive High School Internships of America, "Director's Annual Report to the National Advisory Board," 1976, 223.1
  - "A Brief Study of the Administration of the Hebrew Academy of Suffolk County," 1977, 343
  - Moon, Rexford G., Jr., "Integrated Bilingual Demonstration Project for High Schools." Office of Educational Evaluation, Board of Education of the City of New York. 1974, 205
  - Moon, Rexford G., Jr., "Louis D. Brandeis High School Bilingual Program." Office of Educational Evaluation, Board of Education of the City of New York. 1974, 205.2
  - Moon, Rexford G., Jr., "Bilingual Program in Auxiliary Services for High Schools." Office of Educational Evaluation, Board of Education of the City of New York. 1974, 205.3
  - "The Future of Public Education in Mansfield." Board of Education, Mansfield, Connecticut. 1970, 77
  - Quality Education in Milwaukee's Future. Board of School Directors, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. 1967, 25
  - "Sacramento Public Schools." School Board, Unified School District, Sacramento, California. 1968, 45 (Box 60.)
  - "Study of Catholic Education in Colorado Springs, Colorado," 1969, 48.4
- Schweppe Research and Education Fund. (Box No. 60.)
  - Conference on Major Transitions in the Human Life Cycle, Aspen, Colorado, 1976, "Background Readings," 1976, 234.1 (Box 60.)
  - Spierer, Howard, Major Transitions in the Human Life Cycle: A Summary of a Conference on the Significance of the Biomedical and the Social Sciences in Understanding the Aging Process, 1977, 234.2
  - Scanlon, John, Young Adulthood: A Summary of the Third Annual Conference on Major Transitions in the Human Life Cycle, 1979, 234.2
- States. (Box No. 61-72.)
  - California (Box 61.)
    - "Governance of Public Higher Education in California." Coordinating Council for Higher Education, State of California., 56
    - "Financing Postsecondary Education in California." Joint Committee on the Master Plan for Higher Education, California Legislature. 1973, 153.1
    - "Interinstitutional Cooperation in California Higher Education." Joint Committee on the Master Plan for Higher Education, California Legislature. 1973, 153.2
    - "A Short Study of the Prospective Federal Government Role in Financing Higher Education for the Decade 1972-1982." Joint Legislative Committee on the Master Plan for Higher Education, State of California. 1972, 154
  - Colorado
    - Directions for the Colorado School of Mines. Colorado Commission on Higher Education. 1968, 26
    - Policy Studies in Education, "Exploring Careers in the Community for Gifted and Talented Senior High School Students." Jefferson County Public Schools. 1979, P-387
    - Metropolis: Muddle or Model? Denver Area School Superintendents' Council. 1967, 51
    - "Outreach and Occupational Education in Colorado." Colorado Commission on Higher Education. 1972, 128